Guide to the Eve Arnold Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- June 2003 Acquisition, 1; 25.9; (70 boxes) + 6 rolls + 4 film reels
  - Audiovisual Materials
    - Video recordings
      - "Eve and Marilyn", undated; YCALMSS611_0014; 1; 01:00:44 (Box 62, Item barcode 39002102349843)
      - "Eve and Marilyn," BBC 1987, YCALMSS611_0015; 1; 00:58:48 (Box 62, Item barcode 39002102349850)
      - "Eve and Marilyn," 1987 October 22, YCALMSS611_0016; 1; 00:31:31 (Box 62, Item barcode 39002102349868)
      - "Eve Arnold - Rush[gs?], 1995, Pinewood Studios, Beebans film on Eve", YCALMSS611_0017; 1; 00:16:25; The time code runs on the bottom of the video. (Box 204, Item barcode 39002102349876)
      - "Eve Arnold exhibition Birmingham Ikon Gallery, 1996", YCALMSS611_0018; 1; 00:04:41 (Box 204, Item barcode 39002102349884)
        A handwritten note is included with the tape. It reads:
        Dear Ms. Arnold, I enclose a long delayed copy of the piece I made on your exhibition at the Ikon Gallery, Birmingham. It was a pleasure meeting you, I hope you like the item - I thought the editing a little too fast! I'm off to South America for two months, and hope to undertake an M.A. at the Royal College of Art. I trust you are well. Regards, Rachel Smart
      - "Eve Arnold at Benhams, British Satellite News", 1993 February 11; YCALMSS611_0019; 1; 00:03:15 (Box 204, Item barcode 39002102349892)
      - "Hardtalk- Eve Arnold", undated; YCALMSS611_0020; 1; 00:32:15 (Box 63, Item barcode 39002102349900)
        Includes note "Throw our? Keep audio?"
      - "Henri Cartier-Bresson: Pen Brush and Camera," copy 1 of 2, 1998 March 23; YCALMSS611_0021; 1; 00:49:52 (Box 63, Item barcode 39002102349918)
      - "Henri Cartier-Bresson: Pen Brush and Camera," copy 2 of 2, 1998 March 23; YCALMSS611_0022; 1; 00:50:04 (Box 63, Item barcode 39002102349926)
      - "Italian TV, Eve Arnold, DSE: Fotogiormalismo No. 2", 1992; YCALMSS611_0023; 1; 00:25:16; There is a slight crackle in the audio. (Box 63, Item barcode 39002102349934)
      - "Italian TV, Eve Arnold, DSE: Fotogiormalismo No. 3", 1992; YCALMSS611_0024; 1; 00:25:33 (Box 63, Item barcode 39002102349942)
      - "'Magnum Story' Prog: 1/2 Decisive Moments/These Savage Years, Dur: 121, 1990", YCALMSS611_0025; 1; 01:04:31 (Box 63, Item barcode 39002102349959)
      - "The Frame program 33, Cartier Bresson 1998 26' BBC", YCALMSS611_0026; 1; 00:27:51 (Box 63, Item barcode 39002102417228)
      - "BBC Frank Delaney Photography, 1984 November 11", 1984-11-11; YCALMSS611_0027; 1; 00:41:23 (Box 63, Item barcode 39002102417236)
      - "Harvey 1-55, Frank Delaney- Photo 1980- Keep", YCALMSS611_0028; 1; 02:40:13 (Box 63, Item barcode 39002102417244)
      - "Jameson Tonight Show 133, Eve Arnold", 1989 November 10; YCALMSS611_0029; 1; 01:00:05 (Box 63, Item barcode 39002102417251)
      - "The Late Show: Paul Strand, Eve speaking", 1995 June 6; YCALMSS611_0030; 1; 00:12:00 (Box 204, Item barcode 39002102417269)
      - "Magnum Photos-50 Years" Channel Four News, 1997 June 26; YCALMSS611_0031; 1; 00:05:16 (Box 204, Item barcode 39002102417277)
      - "Magnum Story" Prog: 3 Close the Edge, PAL VHS, Dur: 69'40", 1990; YCALMSS611_0032; 1; 01:10:58 (Box 64, Item barcode 39002102417285)
      - "The Making of Eve Arnold," parts 1, 2, and 3, 1997 December 18; YCALMSS611_0033; 1; 00:35:57 (Box 64, Item barcode 39002102417293)
      - "The Making of Eve Arnold," part 4, 1998 December 1; YCALMSS605_0034; 1; 00:06:08 (Box 64, Item barcode 39002102417301)
      - "Midlands Today, Eve Arnold Re: In Retrospect, Art File, with Opening/Closing Link's", 1996 September 19; YCALMSS611_0035; 1; 00:07:14; There is a slight buzz in the audio. (Box 64, Item barcode 39002102417319)
      - "Eve Arnold - In Retrospect" by Beeban Kidron for BBC's Omnibus "BK", YCALMSS611_0036; 1; 00:54:32 (Box 64, Item barcode 39002102417327)
      - "Eve Arnold on 'Primetime'", 1991 November 13; YCALMSS611_0037; 1; 00:45:34 (Box 64, Item barcode 39002102417335)
      - "The Peoples Passion," NVC Arts, YCALMSS611_0038; 1; 00:51:35; Time code runs through the video. PAL. (Box 64, Item barcode 39002102417343)
      - "Ruby TX No 2 Arnold/Simpson," copy 1 of 2, 1997 May 11; YCALMSS611_0039; 1; 00:40:52 (Box 64, Item barcode 39002102417350)
      - "Ruby TX No 2 Arnold/Simpson," copy 2 of 2, 1997 May 11; YCALMSS611_0040; 1; 00:39:50 (Box 64, Item barcode 39002102417368)
      - "Tonight with Jonathan Ross, Show 8", 1990; YCALMSS611_0041; 1; 00:28:12 (Box 64, Item barcode 39002102417376)
      - "Eve Arnold on the World Today" BBC World TV, 1996 Summer; YCALMSS611_0042; 1; 00:07:11 (Box 204, Item barcode 39002102417384)
      - In China: Photographs by Eve Arnold, 1980; YCALMSS611_0004; 1; 00:27:35 (Box 65, Item barcode 39002102349728)
        Taped live November 1980 at the Brooklyn Museum. Guest: Eve Arnold. Moderator: David H. Katzive.
      - The Unretouched Woman, undated; YCALMSS611_0005; 1; 00:27:58 (Box 65, Item barcode 39002102349736)
      - 100 Photos du Siecle Marilyn, 1960, English version, undated; YCALMSS611_0001; 1; 00:06:32; PAL (Box 66, Item barcode 39002102349694)
      - 100 Photos de Siecle Marilyn, 1960, French version, undated; YCALMSS611_0002; 1; 00:06:50; PAL (Box 66, Item barcode 39002102349702)
      - "Eve Arnold with Mary Parkinson", undated; 1 (Box 66, Item barcode 39002102349710)
    - Motion picture films
      - Behind the Veil; original container for New York film versions, circa 1971 (Box 67)
      - Behind the Veil; original containers for 16 mm color print versions, circa 1971 (Box 67a)
      - Behind the Veil: 16 mm film labeled "Head - Protection Print - Harem," New York version, circa 200 feet, circa 1971 (Box 68 (Cold storage))
      - Behind the Veil: 16 mm film labeled "Chronolog - protrk - Harem - Head," New York version, circa 200 feet, circa 1971 (Box 69 (Cold storage))
      - Behind the Veil: 16 mm color print, 2400 feet, circa 1971 (Box 70 (Cold storage))
      - Behind the Veil: 16 mm film, 2400 feet, circa 1971 (Box 71 (Cold storage))
  - Electronic Media, (6 computer disks)
    Restricted fragile material. Reference copies of electronic files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
    - 2003-ycal-0626-a-0001: In Retrospect back-up 9 August 94, 1994 (Box 72)
      3 1/4 inch computer disk
    - 2003-ycal-0626-a-0002-0005: Retro 2-5, 1996 (Box 72)
      Optical disks with high-resolution continuous tone digital files of photographs and text for Arnold's book In Retrospect
    - 2003-ycal-0626-a-0006: John Tusa interview with Eve Arnold, BBC, undated (Box 72)
      Compact disc
- August 2004 Acquisition, 2; 47; (64 boxes)
  Former call number: Uncat MSS 692
  Box 134 (sound and video recordings): Use of originals is restricted. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  Organized under six headings: Book Projects; Contact Sheets; Mixed Contact Sheets, Negatives, and Transparencies; Negatives; Slides; Other Papers
  Contains photographs, including contact sheets, slides, negatives, and audiovisual materials
  - Book Projects
    Contains contact sheets, slides, and negatives used by Arnold in preparing publications
    - All in a Day's Work, In China, Portrait of a Film, Private View (Box 73)
    - The Unretouched Woman (Box 74)
    - Flashback: the 50s, Great British, In America, In Retrospect (Box 75)
    - All in a Day's Work, Film Journal, Flashback: the 50s, How America Lives (Box 76)
  - Contact Sheets
    - 1950s subjects A-Z; story numbers 51-1 through 52-4, 1950-1952; (3 binders) (Box 77)
    - Story numbers 52-5 through 56-3, 1952-1956; (5 binders) (Box 78)
    - Story numbers 56-4 through 58-2, 1956-1958; (3 binders) (Box 79)
    - Story numbers 58-3 through 58-21, 1958; (2 binders) (Box 80)
    - Story numbers 59-1 through 61-15, 1959-1961; (4 binders) (Box 81)
    - Story numbers 61-16 through 63-9, 1961-1963; (5 binders) (Box 82)
    - Story numbers 63-10 through 65-20, 1963-1965; (5 binders) (Box 83)
    - Story numbers 66-1 through 67-4, 1966-1967; (5 binders) (Box 84)
    - Story numbers 67-5 through 77-19, 1967-1977; (5 binders) (Box 85)
    - Story numbers 78-1 through 00-1, 1978-2000; (4 binders) (Box 86)
  - Mixed Contact Sheets, Negatives, and Transparencies
    - Story numbers 57-7, 57-9, 57-12, 57-13, 57-14, 57-15, 57-16, 57-17, 57-24, 1957; 5 (Box 87)
    - Miscellaneous, 1950s; 6 (Box 88)
    - Miscellaneous, undated; 2 (Box 89)
  - Negatives
    Arranged chronologically and primarily by story number
    - Unidentified 1950s (Box 90)
    - Unidentified 1950s (Box 91)
    - 1950s subjects: A through United States (Box 92)
    - 1950s subjects: Verdon; story numbers in 1953 (Box 93)
    - 1954 through 1955 (Box 94)
    - 1956 through 1957 (Box 95)
    - 1958 (Box 96)
    - 1959 (Box 97)
    - 1960 through 1961-10 (Box 98)
    - 1961-10 through 1962-13 (Box 99)
    - 1962-13 through 1963-9 (Box 100)
    - 1963-9 through 1964-2 (Box 101)
    - 1964-3 through end 1964 (Box 102)
    - 1965 (Box 103)
    - 1965 through 1966-16 (Box 104)
    - 1966-17 through end 1966 (Box 105)
    - 1967 through 1968 (Box 106)
    - 1969 through 1972 (Box 107)
    - 1973 through 1978 (Box 108)
    - 1979 through 1987 (Box 109)
    - 1989 through 2000 (Box 110)
    - Color transparencies from Bonhams sale catalog; contact sheets and negatives of The Crucible film set, 6 (Box 111)
    - Empty boxes for Bonhams catalog material and The Crucible (Box 112)
  - Slides
    Housed in binders and slide boxes
    - "Films" A-O (Box 113)
    - "Films" P-W (Box 114)
    - "Personalities" A-Ho (Box 115)
    - "Personalities" Hu-Z; "Personalities second choice" (Box 116)
    - Afghanistan, African Village (Box 117)
    - Aran Islands, Arabs, China (Box 118)
    - China, Cuba, India (first trip) (Box 119)
    - India (second trip), Europe, Egypt (Box 120)
    - France/Monaco, South Africa, Trucial States (United Arab Emirates), Tunisia (Box 121)
    - U.K. (Box 122)
    - U.K., United States (Box 123)
    - Soviet Union, Yugoslavia (Box 124)
    - Landscapes, second choice fashion (Box 125)
    - 1950s-1970s (Box 126)
    - 1970s; miscellaneous (Box 127)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 128)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 129)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 130)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 131)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 132)
  - Other Papers
    - Print inventory binders (3), Castelli inventory binder and project book orders binder; covers of English edition of An Unretouched Woman, 1977, 1991, undated (Box 133)
    - Audiovisual materials
      Material in Box 134 (except slides) is use restricted.
      - Behind the Veil, copy 1 of 3, circa 1971; YCALMSS611_0006; 1; 00:58:06 (Box 134, Item barcode 39002102349744)
      - Behind the Veil, copy 2 of 3, 1; Not digitized. (Box 134, Item barcode 39002102349751)
      - Behind the Veil, copy 3 of 3, 1; Not digitized. (Box 134, Item barcode 39002102349769)
      - Behind the Veil, undated; 3 (Box 134)
      - In China slides, undated (Box 134)
    - Dashboard contact prints and story boards for Russian film; story ideas, undated (Box 135)
    - Dashboard contact prints and story boards for Russian film; story ideas, undated (Box 136)
- June 2005 Acquisition, 3; 10.5; (59 boxes)
  Former call number: Uncat MSS 777
  Organized under two headings: Contact Sheets; Other Material
  Contains photographs, including contact sheets, work prints, slides, and negatives. The first group of contact sheets are filed in chronological order; the second group of other material is arranged by subject or project title.
  - Contact Sheets
    Arranged by story number; see story list log in box 137 for subjects associated with story numbers. Many prints remain in Arnold's commercial photo paper boxes.
    - Story list (Magnum master file kept by Arnold), 1950-1994 (Box 137)
    - Story list (photocopies), undated (Box 137)
    - 51-1, 1951; 2 (Box 137)
    - 52-1, 52-2, 52-9, 52-11, 1952; 4 (Box 137)
    - 54-1, 1954 (Box 137)
    - 54-5, 1954 (Box 138)
    - 55-2, 56-3, 56-5, 56-9, 56-11, 57-1, 57-21, 58-1, 58-2, 58-4, 58-7, 58-11, 58-15, 1955-1958; 14 (Box 139)
    - 59-2, 59-6, 59-9, 59-12, 1959; 6 (Box 140)
    - 59-15, mixed 1950s sheets, 60-4, 61-6, 61-11, 62-12, 62-13, 1959-1962; 8 (Box 141)
    - 63-1, 63-2, 63-6, 1963; 6 (Box 142)
    - 63-8, 63-9, 1963; 5 (Box 143)
    - 63-11, 64-4, 64-7, 1963-1964; 4 (Box 144)
    - 64-10, 64-34, 65-2, 65-9, 65-10, 65-12, 65-13, 65-19, 1965; 12 (Box 145)
    - 66-2, 66-5, 66-9, 66-10, 66-11, 66-21, 1966; 7 (Box 146)
    - 66-22, 66-23, 66-24, 66-25, 66-26, 66-28, 66-29, 66-30, 66-31, 66-32, 66-34, 66-36, 1966; 12 (Box 147)
    - 66-37, 66-38, 66-42, 66-44, 66-45, 66-46, 66-47, 66-48, 66-53, 1966; 9 (Box 148)
    - empty envelope with miscellaneous notes, undated (Box 148)
    - 67-1, 67-5, 67-6, 68-5, 68-9, 68-10, mixed sheets from 1968, 1967-1968; 8 (Box 149)
    - 69-3, 69-13, mixed sheets from 1969, 70-12, 70-22, 71-10, 72-6, 1969-1972; 8 (Box 149)
  - Other Material
    - Great Britain
      - Black and white [work prints] with captions, 1961 (Box 150)
      - Black and white [work prints] with captions, 1962 (Box 151)
      - Black and white [work prints] with captions, 1963 (Box 152)
    - Handbook (with Footnotes)
      - Original slides and copy of published book (London: 2004), 2004, undated; 2 (Box 153)
      - Original slides and duplicates, undated (Box 154)
      - Slides, undated (Box 155)
      - Slides, undated (Box 156)
      - Slides, undated (Box 157)
    - The Misfits and Marilyn Monroe
      - 60-20, work prints and contact prints, 1960; 13 (Box 158)
      - Contact sheet notebook, 1960 (Box 159)
      - 60-13 through 60-20, contact sheet notebook, 1960 (Box 160)
      - 60-20, negatives #1-145, 1960; 10 (Box 161)
      - 60-20, negatives #146-213, 1960; 4 (Box 162)
      - Marilyn Monroe slides, undated (Box 163)
      - "Marilyn from book, copy negatives, lith. from printer, etc.," slides, Polaroid prints, undated (Box 164)
    - Private View: Inside Baryshnikov's American Ballet Theatre
      - Original prints used for book, 1987 (Box 165)
      - Prints chosen for exhibition at Leo Castelli, New York, 1987 (Box 166)
      - Duplicate prints, incomplete set, 1987 (Box 167)
      - Extra prints, 1987 (Box 168)
      - Extra prints, 1987 (Box 169)
      - Additional prints, 1987; 68 (Box 170)
      - Additional prints, 1987; 7 (Box 171)
        Includes four folders with Bantam editorial flags attached
    - In Retrospect
      - Photographs with captions, 1950 (Box 172)
      - Photographs with captions, 1951-1953 (Box 173)
      - Photographs with captions, 1954-1955 (Box 174)
      - Photographs with captions, 1956-1957 (Box 175)
      - Photographs with captions, 1958 (Box 176)
      - Photographs with captions, 1959 (Box 177)
      - Photographs with captions, 1950s (Box 178)
      - Photographs with captions, 1960 (Box 179)
      - Photographs with captions, 1960 (Box 180)
      - Photographs with captions, 1961 (Box 181)
      - Photographs with captions, 1964 (Box 182)
      - Photographs with captions, 1964 (Box 183)
      - Photographs with captions, 1965 (Box 184)
      - Photographs with captions, 1965 (Box 185)
      - Photographs with captions, 1966 (Box 186)
      - Photographs with captions, 1967 (Box 187)
      - Photographs with captions, 1968-1969 (Box 188)
      - Photographs with captions, 1970-1971 (Box 189)
      - Photographs with captions, 1972-1976 (Box 190)
      - Photographs with captions, 1977 (Box 191)
      - Photographs with captions, 1978-1979 (Box 192)
      - Photographs with captions, 1980s (Box 193)
      - Photographs with captions, 1990s (Box 194)
    - Negatives and contact sheets (all projects and years) returned from Magnum Photos; to be interfiled, undated (Box 195)
- June 2006 Acquisition, Series IV; 0.5; (2 boxes)
  Former call number: Uncat MSS 871
  Contains photographs, contact sheets, negatives, slides, transparencies, work copy, and notes related to the 2005 edition of Marilyn Monroe: an Appreciation.
  - Photographic material, 1950-1961; 5 (Box 196)
  - Copy of book annotated with Arnold's original negative numbers and references to the 1987 edition, 2005 (Box 197)
  - Related paper printouts, 2005 (Box 197)